[
{
    "question": "African civilization had a variety of hairstyles that were used as a symbol of tribal traditions and conveyed a message of age, marital status, _______________, and rank.",
    "optionA": "political position",
    "optionB": "religious beliefs",
    "optionC": "power",
    "optionD": "education",
    "answer": "power"
},
{
    "question": "Short-term goals are those goals that can generally be completed within one _______________ or less.",
    "optionA": "day",
    "optionB": "year",
    "optionC": "month",
    "optionD": "week",
    "answer": "year"
},
{
    "question": "While working, your clothing should always be stylish, comfortable, and _________________.",
    "optionA": "highly accessorized",
    "optionB": "formal",
    "optionC": "functional",
    "optionD": "colorful",
    "answer": "functional"
},
{
    "question": "Good communication skills reduce potential workplace _______________.",
    "optionA": "harmony",
    "optionB": "compatibility",
    "optionC": "conflict",
    "optionD": "consistency",
    "answer": "conflict"
},
{
    "question": "Cocci are bacteria that are ___________.",
    "optionA": "round-shaped",
    "optionB": "rod-shaped",
    "optionC": "corkscrew-shaped",
    "optionD": "spore-shaped",
    "answer": "round-shaped"
},
{
    "question": "The basic units of all living things, from bacteria to plants to animals, including human beings, are ________________.",
    "optionA": "organs",
    "optionB": "cells",
    "optionC": "muscles",
    "optionD": "nerves",
    "answer": "cells"
},
{
    "question": "A physician who specializes in diseases and disorders of the skin, hair, and nails is _____________.",
    "optionA": "a histologist",
    "optionB": "a dermatologist",
    "optionC": "an esthetician",
    "optionD": "a pediatrician",
    "answer": "a dermatologist"
},
{
    "question": "Many scientists and dermatologists believe that extrinsic factors such as exposure to the sun or smoking are responsible for up to ________ percent of skin aging.",
    "optionA": "50",
    "optionB": "60",
    "optionC": "75",
    "optionD": "85",
    "answer": "85"
},
{
    "question": "A normal, healthy nail surface _____________.",
    "optionA": "is completely inflexible",
    "optionB": "has a spotted surface",
    "optionC": "is shiny and smooth",
    "optionD": "is white and opaque",
    "answer": "is shiny and smooth"
},
{
    "question": "A normal, healthy nail is firm but flexible and should be ___________.",
    "optionA": "smooth and unspotted",
    "optionB": "uneven with few ridges",
    "optionC": "long with a satin finish",
    "optionD": "short and opaque",
    "answer": "smooth and unspotted"
},
{
    "question": "The scientific study of hair, its diseases, and care is called ___________.",
    "optionA": "dermatology",
    "optionB": "trichology",
    "optionC": "biology",
    "optionD": "cosmetology",
    "answer": "trichology"
},
{
    "question": "Inorganic chemistry is the study of substances that do not contain the element carbon, but may contain which element?",
    "optionA": "Silicon",
    "optionB": "Oxygen",
    "optionC": "Hydrogen",
    "optionD": "Nitrogen",
    "answer": "Hydrogen"
},
{
    "question": "The movement of electrons from one atom to another along a conductor is called ______________.",
    "optionA": "an electric charge",
    "optionB": "electricity",
    "optionC": "energy flow",
    "optionD": "sparks",
    "answer": "electricity"
},
{
    "question": "Chemically infused services that make changes in the natural texture, curl, or ___________ in the hair are considered permanent and will never revert back to the original pattern.",
    "optionA": "thickness",
    "optionB": "wave pattern",
    "optionC": "elasticity",
    "optionD": "hair color",
    "answer": "wave pattern"
},
{
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of a shampoo service?",
    "optionA": "To recommend additional services",
    "optionB": "To cleanse the hair and scalp",
    "optionC": "To diagnose scalp diseases",
    "optionD": "To analyze the scalp",
    "answer": "To cleanse the hair and scalp"
},
{
    "question": "The reference point that signals a change in head shape from flat to round or vice versa is the ___________.",
    "optionA": "crown area",
    "optionB": "occipital corner",
    "optionC": "four corners",
    "optionD": "parietal ridge",
    "answer": "four corners"
},
{
    "question": "The first step in the hairstyling process is always the __________.",
    "optionA": "cool water shampoo",
    "optionB": "draping procedure",
    "optionC": "client consultation",
    "optionD": "conditioning treatment",
    "answer": "client consultation"
},
{
    "question": "Hair care that uses no chemicals or dyes and does not alter the natural curl or coil pattern of the hair,is known as _____________.",
    "optionA": "chemical-free hairstyling",
    "optionB": "synthetic hairstyling",
    "optionC": "natural hairstyling",
    "optionD": "curl-free hair care",
    "answer": "natural hairstyling"
},
{
    "question":"The fastest way to determine whether a strand of hair is synthetic is to _____________.",
    "optionA": "burn it with a match",
    "optionB": "contact the manufacturer",
    "optionC": "cut it with scissors",
    "optionD": "wet and blow dry it",
    "answer": "burn it with a match"
},
{
    "question": "The chemical texture service that loosens overly curly hair or changes tightly curly or coiled hair into loose curls or waves is ______________.",
    "optionA": "curl softening",
    "optionB": "curl re-forming",
    "optionC": "alternate waving",
    "optionD": "swelling compound",
    "answer": "curl re-forming"
},
{
    "question": "The layer of the hair that gives the hair the majority of its strength and elasticity is the ___________.",
    "optionA": "cortex",
    "optionB": "cuticle",
    "optionC": "follicle",
    "optionD": "medulla",
    "answer": "cortex"
},
{
    "question": "During the client consultation, all clients should complete a client intake form that discloses ________________.",
    "optionA": "topical",
    "optionB": "oral",
    "optionC": "both oral and topical",
    "optionD": "allery medicines",
    "answer": "both oral and topical"
},
{
    "question": "When removing a cleanser from the eye area, it should be done with damp facial sponges or cotton pads ____________.",
    "optionA": "in upward and outward movements",
    "optionB": "in down and across movements",
    "optionC": "with back-and-forth movements",
    "optionD": "in circular movements",
    "answer": "in upward and outward movements"
},
{
    "question": "A ______________ foundation provides heavier coverage and is usually intended for drier, more mature skin types.",
    "optionA": "water-based",
    "optionB": "cream",
    "optionC": "powder",
    "optionD": "gel",
    "answer": "cream"
},
{
    "question": "An adjustable lamp is attached to the manicuring table and should use a ____________ incandescent bulb or a fluorescent bulb.",
    "optionA": "10- to 30-watt",
    "optionB": "40- to 60-watt",
    "optionC": "70- to 90-watt",
    "optionD": "100- to 120-watt",
    "answer": "40- to 60-watt"
},
{
    "question": "When performing a foot massage during a pedicure, you should grasp the foot between your thumb and fingers at the ____________.",
    "optionA": "bottom of the foot",
    "optionB": "heel area",
    "optionC": "mid-tarsal area",
    "optionD": "ankle area",
    "answer": "mid-tarsal area"
},
{
    "question": "A _____________ is a plastic, pre-molded nail shaped from a tough polymer made from acrylonitrile butadiene styrene (ABS) plastic.",
    "optionA": "nail wrap",
    "optionB": "nail tip",
    "optionC": "nail overlay",
    "optionD": "nail adhesive",
    "answer": "nail tip"
},
{
    "question": "Sculptured nails are created by combining a chemical known as monomer liquid mixed with ___________ to form a nail enhancement.",
    "optionA": "monomer powder",
    "optionB": "polymer powder",
    "optionC": "liquid powder",
    "optionD": "molecular powder",
    "answer": "polymer powder"
},
{
    "question": "A(n) _________ is a short chain of monomer liquids that is often thick, sticky, and gel-like and is not long enough to be considered a polymer.",
    "optionA": "post-polymer",
    "optionB": "methacrylate",
    "optionC": "oligomer",
    "optionD": "resin",
    "answer": "oligomer"
},
{
    "question": "The typical independent salon has about ___________ styling staions.",
    "optionA": "three",
    "optionB": "five",
    "optionC": "ten",
    "optionD": "forty",
    "answer": "five"
},
{
    "question": "It is recommended that you select which of these people as a role model?",
    "optionA": "A friend",
    "optionB": "A stylist in the salon",
    "optionC": "A client",
    "optionD": "A vendor",
    "answer": "A stylist in the salon"
},
{
    "question": "When gathering accurate financial information for purchasing an existing salon, it is often helpful to consult with a(n) _________________.",
    "optionA": "interior designer",
    "optionB": "attorney",
    "optionC": "architect",
    "optionD": "certified public accountant",
    "answer": "certified public accountant"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following civilizations was the first to infuse essential oils from the leaves, bark, and blossoms of plants for use as perfumes and for purification purposes?",
    "optionA": "Chinese",
    "optionB": "Egyptians",
    "optionC": "Romans",
    "optionD": "Greeks",
    "answer": "Egyptians"
},
{
    "question": "Which of these terms refers to the moral principles by which we live and work?",
    "optionA": "Equality",
    "optionB": "Emotions",
    "optionC": "Ethics",
    "optionD": "Justice",
    "answer": "Ethics"
},
{
    "question": "Your ____________ involves your posture and the way you walk and move.",
    "optionA": "physical fitness",
    "optionB": "physical presentation",
    "optionC": "physical problems",
    "optionD": "physcial activity",
    "answer": "physical presentation"
},
{
    "question": "In handling a client who is dissatisfied with a service, the ultimate goal is to ___________.",
    "optionA": "convince the client that you are right and she is wrong",
    "optionB": "make the client happy and willing to return for future services",
    "optionC": "get the client out of the salon as quickly as possible",
    "optionD": "fully satisfy the client, regardless of the cost",
    "answer": "make the client happy and willing to return for future services"
},
{
    "question": "Which type of bacteria can cause strep throat or blood poisoning?",
    "optionA": "Diplococci",
    "optionB": "Spirilla",
    "optionC": "Bacilli",
    "optionD": "Streptococci",
    "answer": "Streptococci"
},
{
    "question": "The dense, active protoplasm found in the center of the cell is the ________________.",
    "optionA": "cytoplasm",
    "optionB": "cell membrane",
    "optionC": "nucleus",
    "optionD": "chromatid",
    "answer": "nucleus"
},
{
    "question": "Healthy skin has __________ texture and is smooth.",
    "optionA": "a fine-grained",
    "optionB": "a dry",
    "optionC": "a rough",
    "optionD": "an inflexible",
    "answer": "a fine-grained"
},
{
    "question": "It is recommended that you wear a broad-spectrum sunscreen with an SPF of at least ____ on a daily basis.",
    "optionA": "5",
    "optionB": "8",
    "optionC": "15",
    "optionD": "30",
    "answer": "15"
},
{
    "question": "The portion of the living skin that supports the nail plate as it grows toward the free edge is called the __________.",
    "optionA": "nail bed",
    "optionB": "cuticle",
    "optionC": "matrix",
    "optionD": "ligament",
    "answer": "nail bed"
},
{
    "question": "If a client has ridges running vertically down the length of the natural nail plate, it is recommended that you ___________.",
    "optionA": "aggressively file the nail plate",
    "optionB": "carefully buff the nail plate",
    "optionC": "thin the nail plate",
    "optionD": "remove the free edge",
    "answer": "carefully buff the nail plate"
},
{
    "question": "The two parts of a mature strand of human hair are the ____________.",
    "optionA": "dermis and epidermis",
    "optionB": "hair shaft and hair follicle",
    "optionC": "hair root and hair shaft",
    "optionD": "hair root and hair follicle",
    "answer": "hair root and hair shaft"
},
{
    "question": "A substance that cannot be broken down into simpler substances without a loss of identity is ________________.",
    "optionA": "a compound",
    "optionB": "an ion",
    "optionC": "a molecule",
    "optionD": "an element",
    "answer": "an element"
},
{
    "question": "Electric wires can be covered with a material that does not transmit electricity such as a rubber or plastic coating. This material is known as _____________.",
    "optionA": "an insulator",
    "optionB": "a conductor",
    "optionC": "a circuit",
    "optionD": "a fuse",
    "answer": "an insulator"
},
{
    "question": "For a client with gold skin tones, __________ haircolors are more flattering.",
    "optionA": "contrasting",
    "optionB": "toned",
    "optionC": "warm",
    "optionD": "cool",
    "answer": "warm"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is classified as a universal solvent?",
    "optionA": "Salt",
    "optionB": "Soap",
    "optionC": "Lye",
    "optionD": "Water",
    "answer": "Water"
},
{
    "question": "The straight lines used to build weight and create one-length and low-elevation haircuts are ____________.",
    "optionA": "parallel lines",
    "optionB": "horizontal lines",
    "optionC": "weight lines",
    "optionD": "diagonal lines",
    "answer": "horizontal lines"
},
{
    "question": "The process of shaping and directing the hair into an S pattern through the use of the fingers, combs, and finger-waving lotion is called ___________.",
    "optionA": "hairstyling",
    "optionB": "finger waving",
    "optionC": "ridge curls",
    "optionD": "roller setting",
    "answer": "finger waving"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following braid style or length is recommended for a client with a square face?",
    "optionA": "A style with more width at the sides",
    "optionB": "A style with height",
    "optionC": "Using bangs or sweep braids across the forehead",
    "optionD": "Framing the face with longer braids",
    "answer": "Framing the face with longer braids"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of synthetic hair?",
    "optionA": "Synthetic hair always looks unnatural.",
    "optionB": "Synthetic hair is more expensive than human hair",
    "optionC": "Synthetic hair cannot be exposed to extreme heat",
    "optionD": "Synthetic hair is more prone to fading",
    "answer": "Synthetic hair cannot be exposed to extreme heat"
},
{
    "question": "The layer of the hair that provides the strength and elasticity of human hair is the ___________.",
    "optionA": "medulla",
    "optionB": "regular",
    "optionC": "cortex",
    "optionD": "arrector",
    "answer": " cortex"
},
{
    "question": "In individual hair strands, hair texture is determined by the ____________.",
    "optionA": "density",
    "optionB": "porosity",
    "optionC": "diameter",
    "optionD": "length",
    "answer": "diameter"
},
{
    "question": "An absolute requirement for laser hair removal is that the hair being removed must be ___________.",
    "optionA": "lighter than the surrounding skin",
    "optionB": "darker than the surrounding skin",
    "optionC": "in the anagen phase",
    "optionD": "in the catagen phase",
    "answer": "darker than the surrounding skin"
},
{
    "question": "When performing a skin analysis with a magnifying lamp, the first thing the technician should look for is the presence or absence of ______________.",
    "optionA": "closed comedones",
    "optionB": "visible pores",
    "optionC": "evaporated cells",
    "optionD": "oily skin areas",
    "answer": "visible pores"
},
{
    "question": "A ____________ works well to apply and blend foundation, cream or powder blush, pressed powder, or concealer.",
    "optionA": "spatula",
    "optionB": "sponge",
    "optionC": "cotton pad",
    "optionD": "cotton swab",
    "answer": "sponge"
},
{
    "question": "Fine-grit abrasives are designed for removing very fine scratches and ___________.",
    "optionA": "buffing and polishing",
    "optionB": "smoothing and refining",
    "optionC": "aggressive buffing",
    "optionD": "shortening and shaping",
    "answer": "buffing and polishing"
},
{
    "question": "Hot stones used in pedicures are smooth and typically ________.",
    "optionA": "granite",
    "optionB": "basalt",
    "optionC": "quartz",
    "optionD": "slate",
    "answer": "basalt"
},
{
    "question": "The shallow depression area of the nail tip is the __________.",
    "optionA": "well",
    "optionB": "contact",
    "optionC": "applicator",
    "optionD": "gelled",
    "answer": "well"
},
{
    "question": "As monomer liquid absorbs a polymer powder, the product formed at the tip of the brush is referred to as a ________.",
    "optionA": "cup",
    "optionB": "bead",
    "optionC": "dot",
    "optionD": "pledget",
    "answer": "bead"
},
{
    "question": "What is the most common UV bulb on the market?",
    "optionA": "Four-watt",
    "optionB": "Nine-watt",
    "optionC": "Seven-watt",
    "optionD": "Twelve-watt",
    "answer": "Nine-watt"
},
{
    "question": "Which type of salon shares a national name, consistent image, and business formula that is used at every location?",
    "optionA": "Franchise salon",
    "optionB": "Day spa",
    "optionC": "Value-priced salon",
    "optionD": "Medical spa",
    "answer": "Franchise salon"
},
{
    "question": "The first reality when you are in a service business is that your career revolves around __________.",
    "optionA": "serving your clients",
    "optionB": "making a profit",
    "optionC": "making yourself happy",
    "optionD": "helping your coworkers",
    "answer": "serving your clients"
},
{
    "question": "Another name for an individual owner who determines policies and has the last say in decision making is a _________.",
    "optionA": "business partner",
    "optionB": "stockholder",
    "optionC": "sole proprietor",
    "optionD": "manager",
    "answer": "sole proprietor"
}
]
